Aw c'maaaahn!
Clock yer skinny ass out already, and
let's go get outside some dranks!
Ugh, I can't!
I have to cover her stupid
phone in case those stupid
pirates call with a stupid ransom
demand for Mr. Stupid Archer!
Carol?!
Carol! Have they called?!
No! Ma'am!
But rest assured I'll let you
know the minute they dooo!
Rest?
- My God, who can rest...
- Not me, apparently.
Or me!
I have to re-do the annual
budget because she's blowing it
all on this so-called
rescue of Archer!
Well his plane did crash,
and the distress signal was last
heard coming from a known pirate
fortress, so... - So?!
That doesn't mean Ray and Lana have
to bankrupt ISIS getting there!
Oh, would you relax?
You rent a boat,
that money's gone.
This way, we can sell
it when we're done.
I bet it'll come out cheaper.
I wasn't talking
about the boat.
I think five grand
for the week was a steal.
Look at him, he is lithe.
So a twink escort your rent, but --
That's different!
I mean, they did ask if I wanted to
actually buy him, but I thought...
What, that I'd
be weird about it?
That I, perhaps
due to my race, might have a problem
with the concept of
owning a human being?
I actually just
thought I'd get tired of him.
You?
Mr. Can't Even Commit To A Pet?
Wh-?
Yeah hi, two cats!
One of whom I think has FIP, so...
commit that.
You know how hard I
worked on this budget?!
Nights, weekends, canceled my
vacation, and now it's all wasted!
Wasted, exactly,
let's go be that!
C'mon, happy hour at
Pita Margarita's!
Is...
that what it sounds like?
Only if it sounds like a shitload
of tequila and some A-rab hoagies.
How dare you?!
Arab, sorry.
Oh shut up, how can you
even think about happy hour
at a time like this?!
When probably as we speak, my poor
Sterling is being tortured by pirates!
I wish... What?!
Wish you
wouldn't say that!
- Because I'm sure he's not being tortured...
- Aaaaaaaaaaaagghhhhhhh!
Ohhhh my God, stop, stop, stop,
seriously I can't take anymore!